TIMOTHY OBINNA EWA

Sostware Engineer

\ +234-8164623496

Nsukka, Enugu State, Nigeria

@ ewatimothyobinna@gmail.com

@ LinkedIn/Portfolio

SUMMARY

Enthusiastic Software Engineer with two years of experience. Secures team success through hard work, attention to detail and excellent organization. Brings multifaceted programming knowledge and experience in code debugging. Organised, detail-oriented and consistent in meeting project milestones. Dedicated and hardworking with internal drive to deliver excellence. Hard-working with strong organizational skills. Achieves company goals through exceptional planning and prioritization.

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer

Skyline ICT Consult LTD.

= 10/2023 - 01/2024 Port Harcourt, Rivers State.

ICT and Tech company.

- Developed high-quality software in line with customer-established requirements.
- Created databases, data entry systems and web forms for diverse uses.
- Applied latest standards and approaches to resolve bugs and software errors.
- Designed process flow diagrams and related data processing design documentation.
- Took part in all phases of development processes from project planning to design and launch.

Backend Developer

Skyline ICT Consult LTD.

= 05/2023 - 10/2023 Port Harcourt, Rivers State.

ICT and Tech company.

- Confirmed new features functioned properly and met all specifications and business requirements.
- Identified areas for improvement in existing software programs and developed modifications.

Frontend Developer

Skyline ICT Consult LTD.

ICT and Tech company.

- Performed manual and automated testing to ensure stability across range of devices and browsers.
- Worked closely with backend developers for seamless integration of front-end and back-end systems.
- Coordinated with QA teams to address and resolve front-end issues promptly.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science: Biochemistry.

University of Nigeria, Nsukka.

09/2016 - 02/2022

O'l evel

Fen-Global Secondary School, Ogboji. Ezza North LGA, Ebonyi State.

= 04/2007 - 06/2013

SKILLS

Web-based software engineering.

Software design patterns.

Proficiency in Python and Django.

HTML coding.

SQL.

ACHIEVEMENTS



I have built profesinal sites like content management site, expenses mangement site, etc.

The sites work perfectly well and meet mordern standard.

STRENGTHS



Good collaborative skill.

Acquired from continuous collaborations in building projects with other developers and software engineers.



Multi-tasking.

How did you acquire it? What did it result in?



Pursuit for Excellence.

How did you acquire it? What did it result in?

PASSIONS



Writing codes and debugging.

LANGUAGES

English

Proficient

